# **BRYAN CARR**

#### About Me

As a Software Engineer, I have been able to use my vast troubleshooting experience acquired from years of electronics repair of arcade machines and also maintaining security systems for high-security locations to overcome problems. These general skills allow me to adapt to technical limitations of systems and changing requirements of clients. I believe every problem has a solution—sometimes the key is creativity.

#### Skills

JavaScript, React.js, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Flask, Sketch, Git, GitHub

### **Software Development Projects**

Sept. 2022 - PRESENT

**Baraka -Team Project -** MERN Stack game in which up to 4 players compete to build armies, take over territories, and fight to be the last civilization standing inside of a web browser

- Worked with two other engineers to build a game in a MERN stack that executes in real-time via websocket
- Heavily involved in the back-end database calls, data-structure, and game logic

**Gameshare -Team Project** - Full-stack application that allows users to view and review videogames, and add them to a collection. Users can also view other users' collections that leverages REACT framework

- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested
  all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Implemented routes to a third-party api (giantbomb.com/api) and built scripts to prevent violations to that api's GET limitations
- Helped front-end team members achieve full CRUD for MVP

**Conjure Backpack -Solo Project -** Full-stack application for managing player inventories for the game Dungeons & Dragons. Users can either create Campaigns or join others. Creators can use a full set of seeded items (599 objects), and limit which are available in their campaign as well as add their own. They also have full access to user's inventories who are associated with that campaign.

- Used MongoDB and Mongoose for storing and reading data.
- Utilized Bootstrap for styling.
- Used LiquidJs for live rendering.
- Connected to a third party API to pull publicly available D&D items and seed them in a format that best served the application

**Connect Between 3 & 5 -Solo Project**- Online 2 player game of Connect 4 with the added twist of rotating 90 degrees in a random direction every third round.

- Made entirely with HTML5, CSS, and vanilla Javascript
- All animations were handle via DOM manipulation and timeout functions
- Win conditions, piece positioning, and piece shift after rotate were all determined programmatically

## **Professional Experience**

## **Convergint Technologies** - *Project Specialist Lead*

November 2015 - Present

- Install and maintain security systems for card access, IP video, and intrusion detection from various manufacturers
- Utilize various security software packages
- Exhibits strong technical aptitude across multiple disciplines including electronics, networking, mechanical, and relay logic
- Strictly follow design plans, SOP's, and Life-safety codes for every project

#### Dave & Buster's - Senior Games Technician

August 2013 - November 2015

- Maintained all arcade machines in my store
- Trained technicians in maintenance tasks

### **CCME/FEG** - Store/ Technical Manager

March 2011 - August 2013

- Maintained arcade equipment at three arcades inside of different resorts
- Managed the largest of the three locations. In addition to maintaining the arcade machines, tasks included: hiring, training, and managing employees, budgeting, ordering merchandise, and ordering parts for machines

# **DeNuke Services** - Radiological Controls Technician

March 2008 - December 2010

- Worked on sites in Niskayuna, NY, Grants, NM, and Lemont, IL.
- As a Final Status Specialist, I performed surveys and compiled data to turn over to the Federal Government (DOE) to ensure radioactive clean up jobs were performed correctly, and to the expectations of the DOE.

# **EDUCATION**

# **General Assembly**

Software Engineering Immersive